<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE riscos-prm PUBLIC "-//JMB//DTS PRM documentation 1.00//EN"
			    "http://www.movspclr.co.uk/dtd/100/prm.dtd">
			    
<riscos-prm doc-group="NetSurf User's Manual">
<chapter title="NetSurf Themes">
 <section title="Introduction and Overview">
  <p>NetSurf has inbuilt support for themed icons and status bar tools.<br/>
  This document details how to create your own themes for NetSurf</p>
 </section>

 <section title="Tools Required">
  <p>In order to create a new theme, you will require the following tools:
  <list type="unordered">
   <item><p> A template editor </p></item>
   <item><p> A sprite file editor </p></item>
   <item><p> A text editor </p></item>
  </list>
  </p> 
 </section>
 
 <section title="Creating Templates">
  <p>The best way to go about creating a new theme is to take the templates for the default theme and edit them with a template editor.</p>
  
  <p>The templates file must contain two templates. One is "toolbar", the other is "theme_info".</p>
  
  <subsection title="Toolbar">
   <p>The toolbar template must contain the following icons:
   <list type="unordered">
    <item><p> Back Button </p></item>   
    <item><p> Refresh Button </p></item>
    <item><p> Forwards Button </p></item>
    <item><p> Throbber </p></item>
    <item><p> URL entry bar </p></item>
    <item><p> Status bar </p></item>
   </list></p>
  </subsection>
  
  <subsection title="Theme Info">
   <p>The theme_info template details the theme in a graphical manner. It is similar to a program info dialogue box and should be treated as such. Again, the Default theme is a good source of reference.</p>
  </subsection>
 </section>
 
 <section title="Sprites">
  <p>Sprites should be contained in a single file named "Sprites".</p>
  
  <p>Throbber sprites should display the various stages of progress and should be named "throbberN", where N is a numerical suffix (eg throbber0, throbber 23 etc).</p>
  
  <p>Button sprites can be called whatever you like. The only limitation is that two sprites are provided per button - one unpressed, the other pressed. Also, the template validation strings for each button should contain the sprite names (eg Sbackl,backp)</p>
  
  <subsection title="Optional Preview Sprite">
   <p>You may optionally provide a preview sprite for display in the theme configuration dialogue box. The sprite must be in a file called "Preview" and the sprite itself must be called "preview".</p>
  </subsection>
 </section>

 <section title="Text Files">
  <p>There are two text files which also make up the theme.</p>
  
  <subsection title="Icon Names">
   <p>The IconNames text file provides the link between the template and the program. Each icon has a name defined internally by NetSurf (eg TOOLBAR_BACK). It is necessary to map these internal names to the icon numbers in the template. See the default theme for reference. All icons should be defined.</p>
  </subsection>
  
  <subsection title="Icon Sizes">
   <p>The IconSizes text file is best left alone. Simply copy the one from the default theme into your theme.</p>
  </subsection>
 </section>
 
 <section title="Packaging your Theme">
  <p>The default packaging for NetSurf themes is simply a folder named the same as your theme name (eg "Clear" for the Clear theme). Simply place all the files for your theme into a single directory, name the directory appropriately and create a Zip archive containing your theme.</p>
 </section>
 
 <section title="Submitting your Theme">
  <p>Themes may be uploaded to the central NetSurf theme repository at <reference type="link" href="http://netsurf.sourceforge.net/themes/">http://netsurf.sourceforge.net/themes/</reference></p>
 </section>
 
</chapter>

<meta>
 <maintainer>
  <email name="NetSurf Development Team" address="netsurf-develop@lists.sourceforge.net" />
 </maintainer>
 
 <history>
  <revision number="0.01" date="03/06/03" author="JMB" title="Initial version" />
  <revision number="0.02" date="03/06/03" author="JMB" title="Various changes for clarity" />
 </history>
</meta>
</riscos-prm>			    